

Belfast



linkedin.com/in/dean-john-logan



deanlogan42@gmail.com



https://cv-dean-logan.netlify.app/



DEAN LOGAN

APPRENTCINCE TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT

EDUCATION



- On Track for a 1st for the degree.
- Spent one year as a demonstrator mentoring 1st year students during their practical's.
- Studied modules ranging from web development, network & architecture, to more security-based modules like Secure Software Development and Malware Analysis.
- Participated in various Hackathons including the time my team received Best in the education category for the "Hack the COVID 2020" hackathon hosted by QCS and when I came first in the "Allstate CTF" Hackathon hosted by Queens and Allstate.

Belfast High School (2013-2020)

- A-Level Results:
 - o A* in Electronics and Computer Science.
 - o A in Mathematics.
- GCSE Results:
 - o A* in the following: Computer Science, Electronics, Geography and Double Award Science.
 - o A in Mathematics.
 - o B in English Literature.
 - o C in English Language and Religious Studies.
 - Level 2 in Understanding Business, Enterprise, Languages and Tourism.
- Senior Prefect and mentor.
- Member of the Robotics, Badminton, and cross-country clubs.

SUMMARY

I am a dedicated Software Engineering student at Queen's University Belfast. Through my time at University, I also act as an Apprentice Technology Consultant at PwC, gaining practical experience through my three summer placements (approx. 15 weeks each) and two extensive six-month placements. My technical skills encompass a wide range of technologies, including Java, Python, AWS, Azure, and more. I'm interested in learning more about languages that have a focus on concurrency and speed (like Go & Rust). I also enjoy solving puzzles, reading, playing video games, and cycling in my spare time. For more detailed information about myself you can visit my CV website here.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- I have amassed 7 years of extensive Python experience, beginning during my GCSEs, and encompassing a wide range of projects, including a comprehensive dentist management system, a student module selection and academic progress tracking chatbot developed with Django, and a facial recognition prototype created for the PSNI.
- Another language that I have experience with is Java, this mainly comes from university and placement experience. I have built projects including a cost analysis system for AWS compute instances, a monopoly style board game and autonomous robotic movement.
- During my tenure at PwC, I have cultivated robust communication skills that enable me to adeptly discern client needs and prioritize them in my decision-making process.
- I have a keen ability to quickly acquire new knowledge and a strong dedication to continuously expanding my expertise in cutting-edge technologies. This is shown in my pursuit of certifications during my personal time, covering a broad range of subjects such as cloud computing, AI, and RPA/Process Mining.
- I possess strong collaborative skills honed through my professional journey. I excel in effective communication, active listening, and goal alignment within diverse teams, as demonstrated in my work at PwC and various team projects. Additionally, my experiences as a mentor have enhanced my ability to guide and support team members for optimal teamwork.

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft

- Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900)
- Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900)
- Power Platform Fundamentals (PL-900)
- Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals (SC-900)
- Azure AI Fundamentals (AI-900)

AWS

Certified Cloud Practitioner (CLF-C02)

Freecodecamp

Machine Learning with Python

Digital Acumen Badge

Alteryx

Alteryx Designer Core Certified

Celonis

- Certified to Build Action Flows
- Certified to Write PQL Queries
- Certified to Build Knowledge Models & Views
- Certified to Build Analyses
- Certified to Get Data Into the EMS
- Certified to Identify & Drive Opportunities
- Solution Creation Expert
- **EMS Technical Expert**

AWARDS

FIRST Tech Challenge UK Pioneer of 2020 - Feb 2020

I won the FIRST Tech Challenge in the UK, where teams build and compete with robots in various challenges. My key role was developing the robot's Java-based software, including AI for autonomous tasks such as identifying, lifting, and placing blocks with specific pictures on a platform, as well as parking the robot.

Bronze Duke of Edinburgh Award

This award involved completing six months of volunteering which I spent at a Care Home for people with Dementia, six months of "activities" which I spent in my school's journalism club, and six months of sports which I spent within my school's cross-country club. This also included a two-day hike.

JOB EXPERIENCE



Technology Consultant, PwC UK, Aug 2020 - Present

I contributed to the development of the Cloud Cost Assurance (CCA) tool, focusing on cost analysis for AWS compute services. I utilized AWS CloudWatch APIs, Gradle, Java, and a Test-Driven Development (TDD) approach. I also took on leadership roles, overseeing Technology Degree Apprentices (TDA) and conducting workshops on Azure DevOps and related topics. In another placement I participated in the development of the "Data Lab Importer" a Google Workspace add-on, streamlining data importing from Company House APIs into Google Sheets, developed using Google App-Script.

In another role, I worked with UiPath and Celonis to automate and optimize financial processes, where I worked directly with the client to best fit their needs. On my first placement, I was part of a team that developed the Tech Delivery Workbench (TDW), integrating project management tools (like Jira and Azure DevOps) into PowerBI.

These experiences enriched my skills in software development, cost analysis, automation, cloud computing and project management, while also enhancing my leadership and mentoring abilities.



Software Engineer (Work Experience Programme), PSNI, Aug 2019 - Aug 2019

During the Sentinus IT Bursary Scheme, I collaborated with the PSNI on various projects, including creating a Python-based facial recognition prototype, setting up the secure cloud storage system Box, and created a GUI for CRUD interaction for the database stored on Box. I also conducted research on handwriting recognition for digitizing handwritten notes. This four-week experience allowed me to improve my teamwork and communication skills while working with PSNI colleagues and Box representatives.



Project Manager (Work Experience Programme), Catalyst/Allstate, June 2019 - June 2019

I participated in the Generation Innovation Reimagining Work Experience Program at Catalyst. Working collaboratively with a team of six students, a Catalyst facilitator, and an Allstate representative, we tackled the challenge of enhancing transportation in Belfast. We navigated through various stages of product design over three days and presented our product to twenty senior staff members at Allstate. Following this, I was selected to deliver a concise three-minute pitch to an audience of over 250 individuals, including representatives from diverse companies and academic institutions like Queens and Ulster.

CHECK OUT MY WEBSITE FOR MORE IN-DEPTH INFORMATION ON **EVERYTHING IN THIS**

